# **GABRIEL DAVILA**

Frontend Developer

Location: Aurora, Illinois Phone: 630-864-0607 Email: gdavila0819@gmail.com Portfolio: https://gabedavila.com/

## **Experience**

#### Web Developer

Freelance - Remote

05/2022 - Present

- Created responsive and scalable web applications for use in different industries and client environments.
- Designed, tested and debugged projects from foundation (wireframes/mockups) to full production.
- Attracted users to websites with professional, user-friendly designs and clean code for high-performance operation.
- Developed websites and web apps with accessibility and compatibility for different browsers.
- Updated layouts to meet usability and performance requirements.
- Teamed on user-centric design strategy in translation of UX and business requirements into useful solutions.

#### **Fitness Coach**

H4 Training LLC - Wheaton, IL

02/2020 - Present

- Consulted with clients to define personal health needs, formulate effective fitness, nutritional or rehabilitation plans and improve overall well-being.
- Lead and instruct groups of 4 8 clients in a fast-paced gym environment, with clients having a variety of backgrounds and skill levels.
- Demonstrate with clarity a variety of movements with progressions/regressions depending on client skill level and/or specific issues (injuries).
- Provide a "white-glove" type of customer experience the fitness programming is top tier, but customer experience and service is what really set us apart.
- Clients come first in every regard, so our soft skills are sharp.

### **Fitness Supervisor**

Planet Fitness - Montgomery, IL

11/2016 - 10/2021

- Oversaw the fitness department of the facility as the head trainer and fitness supervisor, increased class attendance by 50% within first year.
- Led classes of 2 8 members at a time in functional-based exercise training sessions.
- Led tours to prospective members and sold memberships and other benefits.
- Trained fitness and regular staff and led orientation for multiple hires. Created the exercise programming for the facility and class schedule.
- Fostered positive working environment for all employees by encouraging staff members to voice opinions and concerns without fear of reprisal.

## Summary

As a frontend developer who is creatively driven with an endless curiosity, I use my skills to create high-quality applications with great user experience. I am continuously learning and developing my web development and programming skills while seeking meaningful work to create a positive impact. I bring with me highly developed soft skills from working with clients and teams in the fitness industry for 7+ years, such as communication, critical thinking, interpersonal skills, problem solving, self-awareness, customer service, and leadership skills.

#### **Technical Skills**

JavaScript Express.js

React.js Git

TypeScript Rest APIs Node.js Bootstrap

CSS Visual Studio Code

HTML5 Figma

Tailwind CSS UX Design

## Project Sample Links

The Red Door Place (on-going client project)

 $\underline{\textbf{M\&G Clean Pros LLC}} \text{ (finished client project)}$ 

H4 Team Notes (on-going client project)

**M&G Budget Tracker** (finished client project)

Fitness Journal (on-going personal project)

#### **Education**

#### Associate in Kinesiology

**Waubonsee Community College** 05/2016

#### Certifications

Frontend Developer Career Path Scrimba

October 2023